Department of Psychology fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Department of Psychology fonds
1964 - 1980
F-103
88 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Department of Psychology
The Department of Psychology was one of the original departments of the Faculty of Arts when the University opened in 1965. It offered courses in general experimental and applied psychology to undergraduate students based upon recommendations of the Canadian and American Psychological Associations. The Department also offered graduate work leading to the M.A. and Ph.D. degrees.
The department functioned through a number of committees which varied over the years. In 1978, for example they included the Undergraduate Studies Committee, Graduate Studies Committee, Space and Equipment Committee, Appointments Committee, Graduate Admissions Committee, Colloquium Committee, Applied/Clinical Committee, Departmental Tenure Committee, and the University Human Experimental Committee.
The department expanded steadily from its inception. By 1979 there were 25 faculty members offering 60 undergraduate courses and 48 graduate courses. Enrollment comprised 550 undergraduate students and 57 graduate students.
published
Full
Published
Title of the fonds is based on the name of its creator.
The fonds of the Department of Psychology consists of records made and received in the course of administering the department, providing instruction, and promoting research. Activities and topics documented include policy and procedures development; the planning, initiation and administration of curriculum and programs; departmental meetings research achievements; student activities; and faculty appointment, promotion and tenure deliberations. Includes correspondence, minutes, reports, policies, faculty employment records, and other documents.
The materials were arranged according to the original filing system of the department.
Bowman, Marilyn L.; Krebs, Dennis L.; Coles, G. Michael; Bakan, Paul; Blackman, Roger; Weinberg, Hal; Cole, Robert E.; Lyman, Bernard E.; Kendall, Lorne M.; Diamond, A. Leonard
Unknown.
Additional material has been accessioned but not yet processed (as of September 2002: 67 cm., 1977-1982). Please consult the archivist for information about using these materials; restrictions may apply. Further accruals to the fonds are expected from time to time.
Access to some records in this collection is restricted in accordance with Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Legislation. Please consult the unit list and the archivist for further details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- Office files, 1964 - 1980; F-103-1; 26 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records relating to the general administrative and operational activities of the Department as described in the Scope and Content note. Files are arranged according to the original filing system. Includes correspondence, minutes, reports, policies and other documents.
  - General office file indices, 1968 - 1978; F-103-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
    Textual records
    Pending review
  - Admission and Enrolment Information, 1975 - 1978; F-103-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Animal Labs, 1967 - 1979; F-103-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Association, Psychology: C.P.A., 1971; F-103-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Commmittee, B.C. Articulation, 1969 - 1976; F-103-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Committee Information, 1967 - 1979; F-103-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Curriculum, 1971 - 1978; F-103-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
    Restricted in part
  - Demonstrations and Displays, 1975 - 1977; F-103-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Employment - Students, 1975 - 1977; F-103-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Meetings - Department, 1976 - 1977; F-103-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Meetings - Department, 1977 - 1979; F-103-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Meetings - Department Equipment and Space Committee, 1967 - 1978; F-103-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Meetings - Applied Clinical Psychology Committee, 1976; F-103-1-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Meetings - Appointments Committee, 1968 - 1974; F-103-1-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Meetings - Department Graduate Studies Committee, 1971 - 1978; F-103-1-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Meetings - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1969 - 1977; F-103-1-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Meetings - Miscellaneous, 1969 - 1974; F-103-1-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Meetings - S.F.U., 1970 - 1975; F-103-1-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Newsletter, 1969; F-103-1-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Organization, 1969 - 1978; F-103-1-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Policy, Procedures and Directives, 1968 - 1978; F-103-1-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Policy, Procedures and Directives (non department), 1971 - 1972; F-103-1-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 103-1)
  - Psychology Club/Union, 1969 - 1973; F-103-1-0-0-23 (Archival box - small 103-2)
  - Psychology Test Information, 1967 - 1977; F-103-1-0-0-24 (Archival box - small 103-2)
  - Research Information, 1970 - 1974; F-103-1-0-0-25 (Archival box - small 103-2)
    Open
  - Research Grants, 1970 - 1978; F-103-1-0-0-26 (Archival box - small 103-2)
  - Staff Information, 1970 - 1977; F-103-1-0-0-27 (Archival box - small 103-2)
  - Staff - Support, 1974 - 1978; F-103-1-0-0-28 (Archival box - small 103-2)
  - Student Information - Undergraduate, 1967 - 1979; F-103-1-0-0-29 (Archival box - small 103-2)
  - Student Information - Graduate, 1971 - 1980; F-103-1-0-0-30 (Archival box - small 103-2)
  - Surveys and Reports, 1964 - 1978; F-103-1-0-0-31 (Archival box - small 103-2)
- Faculty files, 1965 - 1980; F-103-2; 62 cm of textual records
  Series consists of files related to the appointment, salary, and tenure of faculty members. It includes correspondence, curricula vitae, memoranda and reports.
  - Faculty - A, 1969 - 1972; F-103-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 103-3)
  - Faculty - A, 1973 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 103-3)
  - Faculty - A, 1965 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 103-3)
  - Faculty - B, 1968 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 103-3)
  - Faculty - B, 1973 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 103-3)
  - Faculty - B, 1967 - 1974; F-103-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 103-3)
  - Faculty - B, 1975 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 103-3)
  - Faculty - B, 1975 - 1976; F-103-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 103-3)
  - Faculty - B, 1966 - 1971; F-103-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - B, 1972; F-103-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - B, 1973; F-103-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - B, 1974; F-103-2-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - B, 1975; F-103-2-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - B, 1976; F-103-2-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - B, 1977 - 1978; F-103-2-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - B, 1972 - 1973; F-103-2-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - C, 1967 - 1971; F-103-2-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - C, 1972; F-103-2-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - C, 1973; F-103-2-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - C, 1974; F-103-2-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 103-4)
  - Faculty - C, 1975 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 103-5)
  - Faculty - C, 1966 - 1971; F-103-2-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 103-5)
  - Faculty - C, 1972; F-103-2-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 103-5)
  - Faculty - C, 1973 - 1974; F-103-2-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 103-5)
  - Faculty - C, 1975 - 1978; F-103-2-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 103-5)
  - Faculty - D, 1969 - 1971; F-103-2-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 103-5)
  - Faculty - D, 1972 - 1973; F-103-2-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 103-5)
  - Faculty - D, 1974; F-103-2-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 103-5)
  - Faculty - D, 1975 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 103-5)
  - Faculty - D, 1969 - 1971; F-103-2-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 103-5)
  - Faculty - D, 1972 - 1973; F-103-2-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 103-5)
  - Faculty - D, 1974; F-103-2-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 103-6)
  - Faculty - D, 1975 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 103-6)
  - Faculty - K, 1976 - 1978; F-103-2-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 103-6)
  - Faculty - K, 1965 - 1972; F-103-2-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 103-6)
  - Faculty - K, 1973 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 103-6)
  - Faculty - K, 1965 - 1976; F-103-2-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 103-6)
  - Faculty - K, 1974 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-38 (Archival box - standard 103-6)
  - Faculty - L, 1965 - 1978; F-103-2-0-0-39 (Archival box - standard 103-6)
  - Faculty - M, 1971 - 1972; F-103-2-0-0-40 (Archival box - standard 103-6)
  - Faculty - M, 1973 - 1975; F-103-2-0-0-41 (Archival box - standard 103-6)
  - Faculty - M, 1975 - 1979; F-103-2-0-0-42 (Archival box - standard 103-7)
  - Faculty - M, 1973 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-43 (Archival box - standard 103-7)
  - Faculty - P, 1966 - 1972; F-103-2-0-0-44 (Archival box - standard 103-7)
  - Faculty - P, 1972 - 1974; F-103-2-0-0-45 (Archival box - standard 103-7)
  - Faculty - P, 1975 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-46 (Archival box - standard 103-7)
  - Faculty - R, 1975 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-47 (Archival box - standard 103-7)
  - Faculty - S, 1977 - 1980; F-103-2-0-0-48 (Archival box - standard 103-7)
  - Faculty - T, 1974 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-49 (Archival box - standard 103-7)
  - Faculty - W, 1966 - 1971; F-103-2-0-0-50 (Archival box - standard 103-7)
  - Faculty - W, 1972; F-103-2-0-0-51 (Archival box - standard 103-7)
  - Faculty - W, 1973; F-103-2-0-0-52 (Archival box - standard 103-7)
  - Faculty - W, 1974 - 1977; F-103-2-0-0-53 (Archival box - standard 103-7)